<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DEI | MARKIA SMITH</title>
    <link>markiasmith.github.io/tag/dei/</link>
      <atom:link href="markiasmith.github.io/tag/dei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>DEI</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Markia Smith 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 13:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>markiasmith.github.io/media/monitor.png</url>
      <title>DEI</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/tag/dei/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chat with #BlackinGenetics organizer Markia Smith about Systemic Racism in Science</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-ashgchat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-ashgchat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chat was designed to give a voice to historically marginalized communities to explore the role of racism in genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come chat with BlackInGenetics organizers and engage with ASHG leadership about diversity, equity, and inclusion activities underway within the Society, needs in the broader field, your own experiences, and how we can collectively work to expand the benefits of genetics and genomics research for people everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity Luncheon with Joan Reede and BIG</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-ashgdiversityluncheon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-ashgdiversityluncheon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A luncheon dedicated to bringing together historically marginalized genetics professionals and exploring diversity within genetics and ASHG as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come chat with Joan Reede and BIG organizers to connect with fellow genetics professionals and dicusses how we can collectively work to expand the benefits of genetics and genomics research for people everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlackInData</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/project/blackindata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/project/blackindata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Amplifying Black folx in informatics, data science &amp;amp; coding around the world #BlackInData #BlackInDataWeek Nov 16th-21th&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BlackInGenetics</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/project/blackingenetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/project/blackingenetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BIG is an organization dedicated to amplifying voices and work by Black-identifying geneticists. #BlackInGenetics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact us: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blackingenetics.com/contact&#34;&gt;http://blackingenetics.com/contact&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our job board: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blackingenetics.com/job-board&#34;&gt;https://www.blackingenetics.com/job-board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Relationships to Diversify Graduate Education (BRDGE)</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/project/brdge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/project/brdge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;**Building Relationships to Diversify Graduate Education
**
Founded in 2019 by UNC-CH doctoral student Taylor Y. Dismuke, BRDGE Alliance was designed to be a STEM mentoring program with a goal to bridge the gap​ between underrepresented minorities and the STEM community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current focus of BRDGE Alliance is to develop undergraduate students at Historically Black colleges and universities by creating dynamic relationships with black graduate students at research institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the aim to improve diversity in STEM we will use application of peer mentorship, community, and personal and professional development activities to develop underrepresented students in STEM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Race and genetics: using genetics to fight health disparities</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-geneticslecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-geneticslecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This webinar was designed to help educators educate students on the importance of genetics and the history of racism in genetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetics and genomics are everywhere, therefore it is very important to educate the public. We are entering an era where genome sequencing is much more affordable and accessible, even to those outside a research or medical setting. Anyone can now send off a DNA sample to be sequenced by various companies. It is therefore becoming even more crucial that we educate as many people as possible about what the information they get back means (or doesn’t mean). Most people encounter genetic testing at some point in their medical histories. Consumers face choices regarding genetically modified food. Even superficial advertising campaigns today often invoke ‘DNA’. Navigating the modern world requires understanding how technological developments in medicine and agriculture, many based on genetics, impinge on our daily lives. Looking more broadly, all citizens must have some understanding of science and the scientific process for our society to function. In this lecture, I went over the importance of genetics to the general public, how we can use genetics to study disparities, and applications to research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering determinants of response to PD-1 inhibition in the BBN963 bladder cancer model.</title>
      <link>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2019-bbspseminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>markiasmith.github.io/talk/2019-bbspseminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BBN963 model exhibited mixed response to aPD1 in both experiments, gene expression profiling revealed differences in response between the two groups which allowed us to evaluate differences in tumor immune microenvironment between responders and non-responders, previous evaluation of cytokine/chemokine signaling revealed IL-1, IL-2, MIP-1a, RANTES is upregulated in responders, and IL-5 downregulated in non-responders, More recent studies I have completed shown that IL12 is upregulated in NR.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
