<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python | MARKIA SMITH</title>
    <link>https://markiasmith.github.io/tag/python/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://markiasmith.github.io/tag/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>python</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Markia Smith 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://markiasmith.github.io/media/monitor.png</url>
      <title>python</title>
      <link>https://markiasmith.github.io/tag/python/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutational signature analysis in African American and non-African American women with breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-komentalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markiasmith.github.io/talk/2020-komentalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mutational signatures in breast cancer have been well-studied in populations of mostly Caucasian women. Our lab has shown that Black women are more likely to develop aggressive subtypes including basal-like and HER2-enriched tumors. While the expression data supports biological differences in tumors of Black and white women that lead to overall mortality differences, less is known about the role of mutational signatures in racial disparities. This preliminary examination in a targeted gene panel identified mutational signatures with high accuracy. Suggestive differences in frequency of signatures by race were noted. Ongoing sequencing will increase our sample size to further examine the factors that interact with mutational signatures leading to racial disparities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breast cancer disparities</title>
      <link>https://markiasmith.github.io/project/breastcancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markiasmith.github.io/project/breastcancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will leverage &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cancer.gov/about-nci/organization/ccg/research/structural-genomics/tcga&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA)&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://unclineberger.org/cbcs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Carolina Breast Cancer Study (CBCS)&lt;/a&gt; [20% and 50% black patients, respectively] to study mutational signatures and their role in breast cancer disparities. We will probe established risk factors for breast cancer. I anticipate that by investigating these relationships in a large, diverse patient population, I will identify novel associations between carcinogenic exposures and tumor biology in cancer disparities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver cancer disparities</title>
      <link>https://markiasmith.github.io/project/livercancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://markiasmith.github.io/project/livercancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Identify mutational signatures in liver cancer and assess their relationship with environmental exposures and DNA repair markers, overall and by race/ethnicity. I will use mutation data to identify mutational signatures in primary liver cancer and to estimate the relationship of these signatures to exposure markers and DNA repair (such as aflaxtoxin, smoking, alcohol) emphasizing differential incidence among Asian patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
